<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scotthelm.com</title>
    <link>http://scotthelm.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://scotthelm.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Your Website</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 14:58:30 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 14:58:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Even Now</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/05/22/even-now.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/05/22/even-now</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even now&lt;br /&gt;I can hear my heartbeat in my ears&lt;br /&gt;the need to get the words out&lt;br /&gt;before it&amp;#8217;s too late&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now&lt;br /&gt;there&amp;#8217;s so much more I want to tell you&lt;br /&gt;in the midnight confessional&lt;br /&gt;the silent return&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now&lt;br /&gt;I wish I could see through your eyes&lt;br /&gt;standing on the shore with the boatman&lt;br /&gt;looking back over your shoulder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now&lt;br /&gt;Even still&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always think of you when I least expect it&lt;br /&gt;like a flash in my periphery&lt;br /&gt;that draws my eye&lt;br /&gt;and I sit there, rapt for a while searching&lt;br /&gt;searching for what&amp;#8217;s no longer there&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now&lt;br /&gt;Even still&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgres quick cursors</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/05/15/postgres-quick-cursors.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/05/15/postgres-quick-cursors</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to act on individual members of a set. I also didn&amp;#8217;t want to write a function. In psql, I discovered the DO block. It allowed me to gain access to pgplsql without being in the context of a UDF (User Defined Function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this particular case, I created a table called view_refugees. These were views that were causing my rails migration to fail due to a change in an underlying table column&amp;#8217;s datatype. The plan is that I will create the view refugees from pg_views, drop the views, run the migration, then recreate the views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; do $$declare r record;
  begin
    for r in select viewname, schemaname from view_refugees
    loop
      execute &amp;#39;drop view &amp;#39;
      || r.schemaname
      || &amp;#39;.&amp;#39;
      || r.viewname
      || &amp;#39; cascade&amp;#39;;
    end loop;
  end$$;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO block makes that easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Drone</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/02/10/american-drone.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/02/10/american-drone</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are using the same drone technology we use in Afghanistan here in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.cnn.com/2012/09/25/world/asia/pakistan-us-drone-strikes'&gt;Studies indicate&lt;/a&gt; an enormous loss of life due to collateral damage. &lt;a href='http://web.law.columbia.edu/sites/default/files/microsites/human-rights-institute/files/COLUMBIACountingDronesFinal.pdf'&gt;Other studies&lt;/a&gt; indicate that the total number of deaths due to drones is massively under-reported and that the ratio of civilian to militant deaths is extremely high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the former story, &amp;#8220;the percentage of high-level targets killed as a percentage of total casualties is extremely low &amp;#8211; about 2%&amp;#8221;. And yet here we are, using the same technology that has an effective rate of 2% amongst our own populace. &lt;a href='http://www.express.co.uk/news/world/376732/Man-hunt-for-ex-soldier-who-shot-police-chief-s-daughter-and-killed-policeman'&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Sandy Hook, our president speaks of wanting to protect the children. An admiral goal. Would that he meant not only the children here, but the ones we are killing in the name of our &amp;#8220;national interest&amp;#8221; abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American Dream abroad and at home is quickly becoming the American Drone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awk - It's not just a prefix for "ward"</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/27/awk-its-not-just-a-prefix-for-ward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/27/awk-its-not-just-a-prefix-for-ward</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s kind of a joke around where I work. I saw a data import script my boss had written that used &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt; to preprocess massive data files, separating them into record-type-specific files for use with BCP. Since then, I have (jokingly) declared that the combination of awk and elasticsearch is my hammer, and all problems are nails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for speed improvements for our index import process. Having made said improvements (by parallelizing the tasks - invoking the import process in multiple forks and datasets separated by modulus math), I needed an easy way to keep track of the progress. I already had the processes writing to a log file with this format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;20755 processed 1000 objects ending with: 18000 in 53 seconds&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first number is the process id or pid. Since I had multiple processes running, I didn&amp;#8217;t want to have to find the last entry for each pid and do math to find out how quickly things were going. So I whipped up this little import_stats.awk script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#! /bin/awk -f
# this section happens before any lines are read.
# it allows you to set up variables that you can
# use as the program executes
BEGIN {
  total_seconds = 0;
  count = 0;
}

# the unnamed section here is what is executed 
# for each line. In this case, it&amp;#39;s checking to
# see if a line begins with a number, and 
# incrementing counts and totals on if it does.
# the $9 variable is the ninth column in the 
# data line
{
  if ($1 ~ /^[0-9]*$/) {
    total_seconds += $9;
    ++count;
  }
}

# The end section allows you to sum up, peforming
# actions to clean up or print results. In this
# case I&amp;#39;m printing my results
END {
  print &amp;quot;average seconds per thousand: &amp;quot; total_seconds / count;
  print &amp;quot;total processed_thus far: &amp;quot; count * 1000;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now I can check on progress by typing this from the app&amp;#8217;s root:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat log/import.log | awk -f import_stats.awk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I get&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;average seconds per thousand: 50.4306
total processed_thus far: 432000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux and Unix have so many great tools that have been developed over the years that are rock solid foundations for new things. I found this site to be helpful as I was writing my little script: &lt;a href='http://www.grymoire.com/Unix/Awk.html'&gt;Awk - A Tutorial and Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took no time at all to develop this utility. It&amp;#8217;s simple, saves me time and makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Postgres Magic</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/20/more-postgres-magic.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/20/more-postgres-magic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.0/static/sql-reassign-owned.html'&gt;REASSIGN OWNED BY old_role new_role&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command saved my bacon today. I had to apply some scripts that dropped a couple of database objects. The role I was using did not have ownership of the objects in question, so the script failed. I needed to change ownership so the scripts would run correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REASSIGN OWNED BY does just what it says - log into the database you want to effect, and run the command. It transfers ownership from the old role to the new role for all objects in the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;postgres=# create database ownage;
CREATE DATABASE
postgres=# grant all on database ownage to old_owner;
GRANT
postgres=# grant all on database ownage to owner_wannabe;
GRANT
postgres=# \q

psql ownage -U old_owner -h localhost

ownage=# create table users (id serial, username text, password text);
NOTICE:  CREATE TABLE will create implicit sequence &amp;quot;users_id_seq&amp;quot; for serial column &amp;quot;users.id&amp;quot;
CREATE TABLE
ownage=# create table things (id serial, user_id integer, name text);
NOTICE:  CREATE TABLE will create implicit sequence &amp;quot;things_id_seq&amp;quot; for serial column &amp;quot;things.id&amp;quot;
CREATE TABLE
ownage=# \d
              List of relations
 Schema |     Name      |   Type   |  Owner
--------+---------------+----------+----------
 public | things        | table    | old_owner
 public | things_id_seq | sequence | old_owner
 public | users         | table    | old_owner
 public | users_id_seq  | sequence | old_owner
(4 rows)

ownage=# reassign owned by old_owner to owner_wannabe;
REASSIGN OWNED
ownage=# \d
                 List of relations
 Schema |     Name      |   Type   |     Owner     
--------+---------------+----------+---------------
 public | things        | table    | owner_wannabe
 public | things_id_seq | sequence | owner_wannabe
 public | users         | table    | owner_wannabe
 public | users_id_seq  | sequence | owner_wannabe
(4 rows)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, we no longer have to iterate over objects one by one and alter owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, my friends is more Postgres magic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure Is Bending My Brain</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/05/clojure-is-bending-my-brain.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2013/01/05/clojure-is-bending-my-brain</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first foray into the world of functional programming is going to be &lt;a href='http://clojure.org/'&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced &amp;#8220;closure&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Lisp derivative is not a purely functional language like Haskell or standard Lisp. It is built on top of the Java Virtual Machine (JVM) which gives it a wide deployment reach, and has some conveniences that make it easier to get into for OO heads like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functional programming is a REALLY different way of viewing the problem of how to tell a computer what to do. I am seeing some value from learning about functional programming already. Lambdas, for example, make a whole lot more sense to me now. It solves problems of complexity and concurrency that are difficult in object-oriented systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to learning more about it through &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Programming-Clojure-Stuart-Halloway/dp/1934356867/'&gt;Programming Clojure&lt;/a&gt; and will post anything I find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My entire career has been spent honing my object-oriented programming skills. When I first started out, I taught myself about relational data. Then I moved to imperative programming, creating data-driven websites with classic asp and vbscript. (ugh). I quickly figured out that sucked and moved into Java. That&amp;#8217;s where my love affair with object-oriented programming was born. I cut my teeth with Jrun after a brief detour into CF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love OO. It provides a fantastic abstraction that has allowed me to think about software in concrete terms that are somewhat relatable to my clients. I spent years doing it in C#. And now I&amp;#8217;m doing it in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea how different the implementation is between a statically-typed OO language and a functional language, check this out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='example'&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id='java'&gt;Java&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public class StringUtils {
  public static boolean isBlank(String str) {
    int strLen;
    if (str == null || (strLen = str.length()) == 0) {
      return true;
    }
    for (int i = 0; i &amp;lt; strLen; i++) {
      if ((Character.isWhitespace(str.charAt(i)) == false)) {
        return false;
      }
    }
    return true;
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='clojure'&gt;Clojure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defn blank? [str]
  (every? #(Character/isWhitespace %) str))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expressive and succinct. I am intrigued.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans For the New Year</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/31/plans-for-the-new-year.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/31/plans-for-the-new-year</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made some major changes over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='i_changed_jobs'&gt;I changed jobs.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People do this all the time. I don&amp;#8217;t. I spent 8 great years with the last company I worked for. I think the world of them. We simply had different visions for my future. They wanted me to go into a software dev managment sort of role. That did not appeal to me. I like building things and solving problems. We parted ways as friends, which I&amp;#8217;m pretty proud of. Not only because of the amicability of the parting, but because I recognized its necessity, and was willing to get out of my comfort zone to stay happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='i_completely_changed_my_tech'&gt;I completely changed my tech.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean completely. I am an .net enterprise architect. I have delivered large- scale custom applications to fortune 500 companies. I used ASP.Net, MVC, EF and really enjoyed it. Heck, I even managed to wrangle SharePoint 2010 into a passable externally-facing customer portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, I felt that I wasn&amp;#8217;t learning very much, and that there was a lot more out there. I had played around with Ruby and Ruby on Rails producing the &lt;a href='http://www.stuffsimple.com'&gt;StuffSimple&lt;/a&gt; site. But I knew I was barely scratching the surface. With the changes at work looming, I decided to make the change and jump on the open source wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to a friend who had already made the leap, and as he was working with some people I already knew, I asked to come aboard. They agreed, and here I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my toolset is very different:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  {
    :studio         =&amp;gt;      :vim,
    :dotnet         =&amp;gt;      :ruby,
    :xml            =&amp;gt;      :json,
    :typed          =&amp;gt;      :dynamic,
    :iis            =&amp;gt;      :unicorn_and_nginx,
    :gui            =&amp;gt;      :linux_command_line
  }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on, but needless to say, I have had a steep learning curve, and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='my_plans_for_the_coming_year'&gt;My plans for the coming year&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id='learn_more'&gt;Learn More&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s my key personal key to happiness. It&amp;#8217;s what keeps me going. I plan to tackle a functional language of some sort. Probably Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='write_more_music'&gt;Write More Music&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s something I enjoy very much. I need to do more of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='stay_active'&gt;Stay Active&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a fairly good job last year, but I need to keep it up. This is that reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='cultivate_voiceovers'&gt;Cultivate Voiceovers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year was pretty good, but I can do better. I would love to get on a cartoon, or an audible book gig. Let&amp;#8217;s see if I can do that this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='spend_more_time_with_family_and_friends'&gt;Spend more time with family and friends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game night. Let&amp;#8217;s do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='finish_stuffsimple'&gt;Finish StuffSimple&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a working implementation, but it&amp;#8217;s using dated tech. I want to revamp it with all the stuff I&amp;#8217;ve learned over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s going to be exciting! I wish you many joys and triumphs in the coming year! Happy 2013 all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbows</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/29/rainbows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/29/rainbows</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a song I wrote for my mom. My sister found a picture of her and me dancing at my wedding. It was a beautiful gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had started the melody a while back, but had no lyrics. I put the lyrics together today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in a corner of the room&lt;br /&gt;underneath the moving boxes&lt;br /&gt;in a chest of faded memories there&lt;br /&gt;is a picture of us dancing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after all this time flows&lt;br /&gt;out the door and through the windows&lt;br /&gt;through these tears I look up&lt;br /&gt;and see rainbows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often think of you&lt;br /&gt;in my mind I see you smiling&lt;br /&gt;like a vision of the loveliest smile&lt;br /&gt;that anyone has ever&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after all this time flows&lt;br /&gt;out the door and through the windows&lt;br /&gt;through these tears I look up&lt;br /&gt;and see rainbows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder='no' height='166' scrolling='no' src='http://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F72984244&amp;amp;show_artwork=true' width='100%' /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It's the end of the world, and I feel fine</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/20/its-the-end-of-the-world-and-i-feel-fine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/20/its-the-end-of-the-world-and-i-feel-fine</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was amazed by how much the world didn&amp;#8217;t end today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Four for Twelve Twelve</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/12/three-four-for-twelve-twelve.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/12/three-four-for-twelve-twelve</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It being 12/12/12, I was put in mind of 3/4 time, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few songs in that time signature (technically, some are in 6/8, but if I can count it in threes, I count it. This list is just off the top of my head, and is in no particular order&amp;#8230;and yes, there are 2 Queen songs. Sue me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-lG3nXyI41M'&gt;She&amp;#8217;s Leaving Home - Beatles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hvfzrffto2I'&gt;Manic Depression - Jimi Hendirx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47leRbuaOxo'&gt;Birdland - Patti Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qWG2dsXV5HI'&gt;My Favorite Things - John Coltrane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k1G1xZsLb3c'&gt;Drowse - Queen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qwXtHZeBb7M'&gt;Dead Melodies - Beck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ky1td3_6LY'&gt;Nude - Radiohead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04854XqcfCY'&gt;We Are The Champions - Queen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GPG3zSgm_Qo'&gt;Christmas Time Is Here - Charlie Brown Christmas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interestingly, &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XrkThaBWa5c'&gt;Waltzing Matilda&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t in 3/4 unless you count it in triplets. But hey, it&amp;#8217;s a great song, so I&amp;#8217;m including it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your 12/12/12!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Postgres Shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/11/some-postgres-shortcuts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/11/some-postgres-shortcuts</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id='command_line'&gt;Command Line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
pg_dump &amp;lt;database_name&amp;gt; -s -O -h &amp;lt;host&amp;gt; -U &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; -W -f &amp;lt;path_to_target_file&amp;gt; -n &amp;lt;schema_name&amp;gt; -n &amp;lt;schema_name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-s Schema only, please. No data&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;-O (that&amp;#8217;s an O as in &amp;#8220;Oh&amp;#8221;): don&amp;#8217;t script ownership of objects&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;-h the host. If you&amp;#8217;re on the box with the database, then localhost usually works&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;-U the username that you want to connect to the database with&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;-W prompt me for a password. If you don&amp;#8217;t want this, then you will need to set the PG_PASS environment variable&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;-n schema name. Postgres has the concept of schemas. Think of them as namespaces. You can pass a list with multiple -n or leave it blank and get all of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The -h, -U and -W work with psql as well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='psql'&gt;psql&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;within psql, \e will open your editor of choice. I usually use vim. It creates a file in &lt;code&gt;
/tmp/psql.edit.&amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt; where pid is the process ID of psql. You edit your sql in that file. When you :wq to write and quit vim, psql will use that file as it&amp;#8217;s command. So if you want it to execute, then make sure it ends with a semicolon; or it won&amp;#8217;t run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come. These are ones I&amp;#8217;ve used today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and The Boys</title>
      <link>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/03/me-and-the-boys.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>you@scotthelm.com (Your Name)</author>
      <guid>http://scotthelm.com/2012/12/03/me-and-the-boys</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, I&amp;#8217;m able to get the boys together with me long enough to take a picture. Their reaction to the countdown in the Photobooth app is always unpredictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='me and the boys' src='http://s3.amazonaws.com/ScottHelm/stuff/pics/20121203.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
